<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/china/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/china/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2018-10-31T10:12:32+00:00</updated><id>/china/</id><title type="html">china</title><subtitle>Website for information on the orienteering trip to China</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Day 7</title><link href="/china/2018/10/31/day-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 7" /><published>2018-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/10/31/day-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/10/31/day-7.html">&lt;p&gt;Everybody was of course tired in the morning, but once out training all seemed good. This was a really nice bamboo forest with nothing but leaves on the ground in a lot of places. Unfortunately the map was a bit old because they’d built a fairly large reservoir and a few big tracks since the map was made. Still, it was very nice running. A quick stop at the hotel for lunch and we were off again for teapot making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bus banter/grafting mainly consisted of the Czechs and ACI expanding each other’s vocabulary in each other’s languages. Unfortunately most of the words cannot be listed here. We made teapots out of clay, but there wasn’t time to put them in a kiln so they are for ornamental use only! On the journey back there was further vocabulary exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then had a bit of time to pack before the farewell dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Everybody was of course tired in the morning, but once out training all seemed good. This was a really nice bamboo forest with nothing but leaves on the ground in a lot of places. Unfortunately the map was a bit old because they’d built a fairly large reservoir and a few big tracks since the map was made. Still, it was very nice running. A quick stop at the hotel for lunch and we were off again for teapot making.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 6</title><link href="/china/2018/10/30/day-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 6" /><published>2018-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/10/30/day-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/10/30/day-6.html">&lt;p&gt;The bus departure was 7am to give us time to reach the third and final opening ceremony in Yixing. This was in a park with quite an impressive background to the stage - waterfalls and precisely cut bushes. There were speeches as with the previous two ceremonies, and then a race around the park. It turned out that the park was pretty large, with the longest course being 6k straight line. Most of the forested bits of the park were dark green so it was lots of path running, but we went into lots of interesting little areas and ran through some tea fields too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was off to our third hotel, imaginatively named “Best Hotel” although it was probably the least best of the three, still pretty good though! In the afternoon there was originally more training planned, but everybody had already run quite a lot so it was replaced by just exploring the village where the training was planned with a map. The beginner orienteers had someone experienced with them to practice following where they were on the map, and everybody else just walked with the map and took photos. After half an hour we were back on the coaches for a very quick visit to a bamboo forest national park. We were taken up a small but very well surfaced forest road in a convoy of buggies, had a short time to take photos, and then went back again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We returned to the hotel and had free time for the evening, so naturally the choice was more karaoke. Oliver (the German leader, who can speak Chinese) organised a group of about 50 people to go down the road for this at about 8pm. People gradually went to bed but ACI were still well represented at half past midnight when we decided it was bed time!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The bus departure was 7am to give us time to reach the third and final opening ceremony in Yixing. This was in a park with quite an impressive background to the stage - waterfalls and precisely cut bushes. There were speeches as with the previous two ceremonies, and then a race around the park. It turned out that the park was pretty large, with the longest course being 6k straight line. Most of the forested bits of the park were dark green so it was lots of path running, but we went into lots of interesting little areas and ran through some tea fields too.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 5</title><link href="/china/2018/10/29/day-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 5" /><published>2018-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/10/29/day-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/10/29/day-5.html">&lt;p&gt;This morning we had the second opening ceremony in an old town square. It was quite similar to the previous one, and Meadow made us proud by giving the speech on behalf of the international athletes. There were some Chinese dance performances, and again speeches from important people from the government organisations who had funded the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was followed by a sprint race (about 3k straight line). The terrain was amazing, China is a really great place for old town orienteering. It was along stone streets with wooden buildings, and then plenty of climb was added by going up and down a hill with a temple on top. There were several interesting route choices where steps, climb, straightness of route and length of route all came into play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately when we finished we were told to go to the museum which was a few hundred metres away. At first there wasn’t much enthusiasm since everybody was recovering from running, but after a short while we went there. It was relatively small and contained a variety of Old Things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went back to the hotel for lunch and out again to have a Tai Chi lesson. It was quite a sight seeing 150 of us dressed in plain white Tai Chi costumes. The lesson was good, although slightly hard to follow because of the language barrier, and if you weren’t at the front it could be hard to see. However, most people managed to get some fluid movements going by the end of it and it was certainly a good experience to have, even if we don’t remember how to do it by next week! In most Chinese cities you see people doing Tai Chi in parks and town squares, particularly early in the morning. It’s popular for exercising your body without putting a lot of pressure on it like running does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then had just over an hour to look around the old town, take photos and buy souvenirs/presents, before returning to the hotel again for dinner. Dinner was a quick turnaround before getting back on the bus to go to a local school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zuzka and I had expected a classroom with 30 school children, but we were greeted by perhaps 150 of them in a big sports hall. There was a brass band playing as we walked in, and then were various musical and dance performances from the school. There were also three non-rehearsed performances from us: the Czech group sung a Czech folk song, one of the Norwegians played Pirates of the Caribbean on the piano, and a girl from Germany bravely sung a solo song (after the rest of her team suddenly decided they didn’t want to do it…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was back to the hotel again for some sleep before an early start tomorrow! Well supposedly - most of the ACI athletes went for a karaoke night until a fair time past midnight!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This morning we had the second opening ceremony in an old town square. It was quite similar to the previous one, and Meadow made us proud by giving the speech on behalf of the international athletes. There were some Chinese dance performances, and again speeches from important people from the government organisations who had funded the trip.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 4</title><link href="/china/2018/10/28/day-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 4" /><published>2018-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/10/28/day-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/10/28/day-4.html">&lt;p&gt;All the coach rides today were quite short, the first one being to today’s training, leaving the hotel at 8am (actually 8.30 by the time everybody had managed to get down the lifts). The training was around a nearby village, so there was a mixture of running along dusty concrete streets, tea plantations, and some fairly green forest. There were many dogs but luckily none of them seemed vicious enough to bite, just bark. Ben hung one of the controls closer to the road because he thought nobody would want to go past the dogs there (and he didn’t want to either), but it turned out that Carys was brave enough to go past them and hunt around in the vegetation for a control which she had already run past, thinking (perfectly reasonably) that it wasn’t hers. It was interesting to see some less-posh China, with people doing building work on their own houses and farming in the surrounding fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this we returned to the hotel to get changed and have lunch, and then we headed out again (on time) to see the vinegar museum. The smell on getting out of the bus was rather strong. We went around the museum which included the option for a not-very-nice vinegar tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then travelled straight to go “hiking”. It appears that in China, walking 5km along an almost flat tarmac path is hiking. An electric minibus-like thing also accompanied us which people jumped on and off for a few hundred metres at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then returned to the hotel for some free time and dinner, before one of the Croatians gave a talk about orienteering in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as everybody was about to leave the talk, the lights went off and a cake came in. It turned out Ben’s birthday had been remembered and he was given the delight/embarassment of 150 people singing happy birthday. It was definitely the biggest birthday cake he’d ever had!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also given Tai Chi suits to wear for tomorrow afternoon’s lesson. It is rumoured that on this evening you were forbidden from entering a certain room on floor 14 without wearing your suit.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">All the coach rides today were quite short, the first one being to today’s training, leaving the hotel at 8am (actually 8.30 by the time everybody had managed to get down the lifts). The training was around a nearby village, so there was a mixture of running along dusty concrete streets, tea plantations, and some fairly green forest. There were many dogs but luckily none of them seemed vicious enough to bite, just bark. Ben hung one of the controls closer to the road because he thought nobody would want to go past the dogs there (and he didn’t want to either), but it turned out that Carys was brave enough to go past them and hunt around in the vegetation for a control which she had already run past, thinking (perfectly reasonably) that it wasn’t hers. It was interesting to see some less-posh China, with people doing building work on their own houses and farming in the surrounding fields.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 3</title><link href="/china/2018/10/27/day-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 3" /><published>2018-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/10/27/day-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/10/27/day-3.html">&lt;p&gt;Meadow was bitten by an evil-looking centipede in the night, which much have been rather traumatic but didn’t seem to cause any harm worse than a wasp sting. The hotel owner was very apologetic (even though it was probably us who brought it in from the forest) and drove her and Zuzka to the hospital to get it checked out - they said it was fine. It was a relatively short coach ride to the “opening ceremony” which was happening on Day 3 of the trip, and is actually the first of three opening ceremonies, one in each place we are staying. There were TV cameras and journalists there. Various important Chinese officials gave short speeches, and then there was a short sprint race aounrd the park, about 2k. It started with a few longer, easy legs, followed by loads of very short legs crossing over each other in the middle of the park. One of the most difficult things was actually finding the next control circle on the map! We then had a bit of time sitting in the sun before we went back to the hotel for lunch, and to load luggage into the bus. In the afternoon we went to a museum. Some highlights were a saucy sand pit where you could dig for bones, and a juicy 360 degree film with tilting chairs which made it feel quite realistic. It was then about an hour to drive to Zhenjiang, north-east from Nanjing, where we’d stay for the next two nights. This hotel was very tall, with our meals being on the top floor (floor 29) in a revolving restaurant. We had some spare time in the evening, so ACI went shopping in an underground shopping street in search of fakes of well known brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some information we were given about the city:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the beautiful city of Zhenjiang, a prefecture-level city in Jiangsu Province. It is located in the south of Jiansu Province, on the south bank of the lower reaches of the Yangtze River, and in the western section of the Yangtze River Delta. It was called “Runzhou” in ancient times and was the capital of Jiangsu Province in the Republic of China. Zhenjiang is a core city of the Nanjing metropolitan area and an important part of the national level Southern Jiangsu Modernization Demonstartion Zone and the Jiansu Yangtze River Economic Belt. There are also famous universities such as Jiangsu University and Jiangsu University of Science and Technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known as the “first mountain in the world”, Zhenjiang sits where the Yangtze River and the Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal meet. The Zhenjiang section of the Grand Canal of China was included into the World Heritage List. Zhenjiang Port is the third largest shipping center in the Yangtze River Basin. Besides, Zhenjiang is a famous town of fish and rice in the south of the Yangtze River and there are two 5A0level scienic areas of Sanshan and Maoshan, as well as many scenic spots and historical sites such as Xijin Ferry and Nanshan. In November 2016, Zhenjiang was included into the second batch of National Tourism Demonstration Zones by the National Tourism Administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2017 International Low Carbon Conference (Zhenjiang) was successfully held in Zhenjiang, Jiangsu Province from September 26-28, 2017. And in November 2017, it was allowed to retain the honorary title of National Civilized City after scrutiny. Besides, in December 2017, it was selected as the National Intellectual Property City and ranked 18th according to the 2017 China’s City Comprehensive Well-off index. In Semptember 2018, it won the “2018 Central European Green Smart City Award”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Meadow was bitten by an evil-looking centipede in the night, which much have been rather traumatic but didn’t seem to cause any harm worse than a wasp sting. The hotel owner was very apologetic (even though it was probably us who brought it in from the forest) and drove her and Zuzka to the hospital to get it checked out - they said it was fine. It was a relatively short coach ride to the “opening ceremony” which was happening on Day 3 of the trip, and is actually the first of three opening ceremonies, one in each place we are staying. There were TV cameras and journalists there. Various important Chinese officials gave short speeches, and then there was a short sprint race aounrd the park, about 2k. It started with a few longer, easy legs, followed by loads of very short legs crossing over each other in the middle of the park. One of the most difficult things was actually finding the next control circle on the map! We then had a bit of time sitting in the sun before we went back to the hotel for lunch, and to load luggage into the bus. In the afternoon we went to a museum. Some highlights were a saucy sand pit where you could dig for bones, and a juicy 360 degree film with tilting chairs which made it feel quite realistic. It was then about an hour to drive to Zhenjiang, north-east from Nanjing, where we’d stay for the next two nights. This hotel was very tall, with our meals being on the top floor (floor 29) in a revolving restaurant. We had some spare time in the evening, so ACI went shopping in an underground shopping street in search of fakes of well known brands.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 2</title><link href="/china/2018/10/26/day-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 2" /><published>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/10/26/day-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/10/26/day-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Another early start at 7am, but another two hours of bus time for catch up. This time we were in a forest by a reservoir. It appeared that unlike the previous forest where we were near the army, this time we were sharing the forest with the army. Fortunately they weren’t doing anything which might conflict with our will to live. It was now warm and sunny, as was the forecast for the rest of the week, and the plus side of the rain yesterday was that it cleared all the pollution from the air. Some of the forest was just grass on the ground so was really nice to run through, although there was more green at the far end of the area. This time people did map memory in pairs, trying to pair people from different countries together. As with yesterday, it took longer than expected for everybody to return (although nobody was so lost this time) so a large box of KFC again turned up at the assembly area. We returned to Najing and had time for an hour in the museum there. There was also a very large Chinese school group in the museum at the same time, and various people were mobbed by Chinese teenagers wanting to have photos together, it’s amazing how excited they are to have a photo with one of us! After this people were split into small groups to go and spend the evening with a Chinese family (mostly from the local orienteering club), to get an experience of how they would eat and live at home. Sam somehow ended up on his own, but seemed to survive well, and Rosie’s family got the meeting time wrong at the end, so the rest of the bus was waiting for an hour. The end of a second day packed with activity and again pretty much straight to bed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Another early start at 7am, but another two hours of bus time for catch up. This time we were in a forest by a reservoir. It appeared that unlike the previous forest where we were near the army, this time we were sharing the forest with the army. Fortunately they weren’t doing anything which might conflict with our will to live. It was now warm and sunny, as was the forecast for the rest of the week, and the plus side of the rain yesterday was that it cleared all the pollution from the air. Some of the forest was just grass on the ground so was really nice to run through, although there was more green at the far end of the area. This time people did map memory in pairs, trying to pair people from different countries together. As with yesterday, it took longer than expected for everybody to return (although nobody was so lost this time) so a large box of KFC again turned up at the assembly area. We returned to Najing and had time for an hour in the museum there. There was also a very large Chinese school group in the museum at the same time, and various people were mobbed by Chinese teenagers wanting to have photos together, it’s amazing how excited they are to have a photo with one of us! After this people were split into small groups to go and spend the evening with a Chinese family (mostly from the local orienteering club), to get an experience of how they would eat and live at home. Sam somehow ended up on his own, but seemed to survive well, and Rosie’s family got the meeting time wrong at the end, so the rest of the bus was waiting for an hour. The end of a second day packed with activity and again pretty much straight to bed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 1</title><link href="/china/2018/10/25/day-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 1" /><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/10/25/day-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/10/25/day-1.html">&lt;p&gt;It was a 7am start for breakfast. There was a huge variety of things on offer with both western and Chinese options available. We then drove about two hours to a forest. Parts of the forest were nice and parts had rather a lot of vegetation. It was raining but sitll warm. There were also fequent rumbling noises nearby, which turned out to be neither thunder nor a quarry, but the army doing explosive drills. Once almost everybody was back, Ben was sent on a 7.5k control collection, but one Croatian was still left in the forest when he returned. He wasn’t new to orienteering, but it turned out that he’d got lost, tried to ask a local woman for help, but she thought he wanted to steal her chickens so she chased him away with a stick. He made it back to the start shortly afterwards though so all fine. Lunch was replaced by a KFC delivery to save some time, before we drove back to Nanjing to walk up the Purple Mountain. It was an easy walk up a paved road, but unfortunately there were no views because it was quite foggy. Dinner was our first taste of Chinese dining - sitting at round tables with a wide variety dishes (some nice, some not so nice) in the middle on a part which spins. After dinner we went to a different part of Nanjing where there was a famous old shopping street, where ACI (the Anglo-Celtic Isles) succeeded in obtaining a speaker to supply bus tunes, but failed in bargaining for it. We then headed back to the hotel and went pretty much straight to bed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It was a 7am start for breakfast. There was a huge variety of things on offer with both western and Chinese options available. We then drove about two hours to a forest. Parts of the forest were nice and parts had rather a lot of vegetation. It was raining but sitll warm. There were also fequent rumbling noises nearby, which turned out to be neither thunder nor a quarry, but the army doing explosive drills. Once almost everybody was back, Ben was sent on a 7.5k control collection, but one Croatian was still left in the forest when he returned. He wasn’t new to orienteering, but it turned out that he’d got lost, tried to ask a local woman for help, but she thought he wanted to steal her chickens so she chased him away with a stick. He made it back to the start shortly afterwards though so all fine. Lunch was replaced by a KFC delivery to save some time, before we drove back to Nanjing to walk up the Purple Mountain. It was an easy walk up a paved road, but unfortunately there were no views because it was quite foggy. Dinner was our first taste of Chinese dining - sitting at round tables with a wide variety dishes (some nice, some not so nice) in the middle on a part which spins. After dinner we went to a different part of Nanjing where there was a famous old shopping street, where ACI (the Anglo-Celtic Isles) succeeded in obtaining a speaker to supply bus tunes, but failed in bargaining for it. We then headed back to the hotel and went pretty much straight to bed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Travelling out</title><link href="/china/2018/10/24/travelling.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Travelling out" /><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/10/24/travelling</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/10/24/travelling.html">&lt;p&gt;We all met at Heathrow and flew to Shanghai, changing planes at Beijing. In Beijing we had to give our fingerprints. In Shanghai we had a bit of trouble finding the bus, but once on board we drove 3 hours to Tangshan, a town just outside Nanjing. We played a couple of getting to know each other games on the bus along with the Czech group. The hotel was outrageously nice, with very big rooms and very big baths, and hot springs available although unfortunately we didn’t have enough time to use them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We all met at Heathrow and flew to Shanghai, changing planes at Beijing. In Beijing we had to give our fingerprints. In Shanghai we had a bit of trouble finding the bus, but once on board we drove 3 hours to Tangshan, a town just outside Nanjing. We played a couple of getting to know each other games on the bus along with the Czech group. The hotel was outrageously nice, with very big rooms and very big baths, and hot springs available although unfortunately we didn’t have enough time to use them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">China website online</title><link href="/china/2018/07/11/initial-news.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="China website online" /><published>2018-07-11T14:03:10+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-11T14:03:10+00:00</updated><id>/china/2018/07/11/initial-news</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2018/07/11/initial-news.html">&lt;p&gt;The China website is online!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The China website is online!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">China 2017, by Imogen Wilson</title><link href="/china/2017/12/15/report-imogen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="China 2017, by Imogen Wilson" /><published>2017-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/china/2017/12/15/report-imogen</id><content type="html" xml:base="/china/2017/12/15/report-imogen.html">&lt;p&gt;I was very excited when my Mum told me that my brother and I had the opportunity to take part in the ‘One Belt, One Road’ international youth orienteering camp in Nanjing, China. There would be teams from the Czech Republic, Norway, Sweden, UK and China, of course. The UK team consisted of 6 juniors plus Ben Windsor as our team leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-journey&quot;&gt;My Journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday I rushed home from school to wait for the taxi that took me to St Margaret’s. From there I went by bus to Heathrow where I would meet my brother Nick and the rest of the team. We checked in okay and took the night flight to Shanghai (Pu Dong) where we arrived the next day at 5 pm Chinese time. Although it was a long journey, it meant we got time to chill and get to know everyone, including the Czech team who were also on the same flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On arrival in Shanghai we were given our very distinctive red ‘One Belt, One Road’ sweat shirts and started our 7 hour bus journey to Nanjing where we arrived at Midnight, feeling very tired, and had to get up again at 6 am in time for our first day of orienteering and the opening ceremony!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;orienteering&quot;&gt;Orienteering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I did not find the orienteering too technical, I found the areas very interesting with regards to terrain; and the maps in general were all quite different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The training also differed as it was pretty much like a race every day, but that was ok because you sometimes got to run with a Chinese partner or I just made the course into a training exercise – my partner and I used map memory for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed running with the younger Chinese juniors, although there was a slight language barrier, they were keen and eager to learn more, and they were happy to run and navigate, with me correcting them by using exaggerated hand gestures and using the map. It was really fun. With the older Chinese juniors, like my partner, they spoke incredibly good English and you could communicate just as you would with anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;climbing-yellow-mountain&quot;&gt;Climbing ‘Yellow Mountain’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had my first experience of a night train when we left Nanjing for Huangshanshi at midnight, after 5 days of orienteering, ending with a closing ceremony (where we were all given beautiful medals). You were in compartments of 6 bunk beds; two lots of three going up, making it almost a bit terrifying being at the top and you were surrounded by people you didn’t know, but that was just part of the fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climbing Huangshan or ‘Yellow’ Mountain (1864 m, about 1000m climb) was an incredible experience. It was a strenuous climb of steep inclining steps for about 4 hours, but once we got to the top, the boys and Ben madly decided to go for a run, while the girls decided to venture out on a walk. However on the mountain it got very cold, I’m certain it was -10 degrees C at one point, which may not seem the coldest but it definitely felt that way when I forgot my gloves at the train station, where we had left our big bags at the bottom of the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top, and also as we were walking up and down, we were always greeted by stunning views which quite honestly took my breath away. We spent a lot of time on top of the mountain, climbing up and down different peaks and finding interesting places and sculptures. – The ‘icy cliff footpath’ was a favourite of mine – the name being very literal!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chinese-culture&quot;&gt;Chinese Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone was so kind and friendly, and after learning that hello in Chinese was ‘Nĭ Hăo’ and thank you ‘Xièxiè’, pronounced like ‘sheyshey’, we ourselves were eager to make use of them, in shops, restaurants and even out on the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I didn’t know was that Chinese children drink warm water instead of cold water like us, so when I was at my Chinese host family they gave me some with their amazing food and surprisingly it was quite nice – try some and see if you agree!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chinese-food&quot;&gt;Chinese Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first week in Nanjing, we ate breakfast every morning in a communal eating place where we would have tokens to order around 5 pieces of food each, a variety of sweet and savoury, which we had to order by pointing and we had no idea what we were getting but that made it interesting and by the end we had discovered which ones we liked and disliked. We also got a cup of what seemed to be rice soup or water, which the Chinese drink for breakfast. I thought it was quite nice despite its unusual consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really nice that we got to eat at fairly posh places, since most of the stay in Nanjing was funded by the Nanjing Sports Bureau, and we got a wide selection of interesting dishes each evening and night.
I was amazed by some of the dishes - sometimes we were given whole birds and fish, it was almost scary, but some of the Chinese showed us what to do and how to eat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the time I had completely mastered the art of eating with chopsticks, although I struggled for the first couple of days – but when you’re only given chopsticks to eat with, well you have to manage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sightseeing&quot;&gt;Sightseeing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent a lot of time visiting traditional Chinese markets and shops in Nanjing and walked through old fishing villages and bustling streets with people’s washing hanging across the street, making it very atmospheric. We were given lots of freedom to explore Nanjing, a very traditional Chinese city which I really liked a lot – it didn’t seem westernised at all. 
Shanghai in comparison felt much more westernised. We walked through the French quarters, where my friends and I finally tried a bubble waffle with mango. We also visited an incredible, traditional temple, which was just off the street, and some famous buildings like the very tall oriental pearl tower. We didn’t go up the tower but chose to explore more of the city instead. As it was our last day, we were also getting quite tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-did-i-enjoy-most&quot;&gt;What did I enjoy most?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about the trip was meeting so many new people from different nationalities. I loved learning about Chinese culture which I found very interesting. I especially enjoyed spending an evening with a Chinese family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore I really enjoyed orienteering in areas very different to those in England, like a bamboo forest (such an amazing experience), an orange orchard (we could literally pick oranges fresh off the trees, eating them straight away or saving them for lunch. On the way back we also tried some fresh honey and honeycomb from a hive which tasted so much nicer than anything I’ve had before), a beautiful park with temples and little stone bridges and full of vibrantly coloured Acer trees (my favourite tree!). I also found it amusing that Chinese residents would be fascinated by us, and if we were having our photo taken, then they would take photos of us too, it was almost like having the paparazzi following us. A kind lady also gave us food to feed some birds from our hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-did-i-least-enjoy&quot;&gt;What did I least enjoy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the week we were all a little fed up with Chinese food, mostly due to it just being so different to our cuisine – I was just craving fresh fruit and a salad when I got home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think since there was a lot of travelling on buses when we got there, it would have been nice to have had more time to socialise with the other nationalities, although we did that anyway, but maybe in a more relaxing environment – I was very tired by the end of the week, after a non-stop schedule, with some very early mornings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I will never forget the amazing memories I have made and the strong friendships I have formed, I am already planning to meet up with some of them again soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I would like to thank my family, friends and orienteers from LEI, EMJOS and EMOA who supported me and bought my cakes. One especially huge THANK YOU goes to Ben Windsor, without him the trip would not have been possible. I was also immensely grateful to my friend’s parents, who got me safely home again, thanks to their winter tyres, after being stuck at the airport for several hours because of the snow. At least I wasn’t stranded at Heathrow for days (in some cases) like some of the other orienteers and passengers! It was quite a dramatic end to our wonderful Chinese adventure.
Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was very excited when my Mum told me that my brother and I had the opportunity to take part in the ‘One Belt, One Road’ international youth orienteering camp in Nanjing, China. There would be teams from the Czech Republic, Norway, Sweden, UK and China, of course. The UK team consisted of 6 juniors plus Ben Windsor as our team leader.</summary></entry></feed>